Resume, André Lambert

Freelance full stack developer and solution architect. 13 november 2019

Personal details

E-mail afj.lambert@gmail.com

Phone +31 624371220

Address Wolfpad 40, Alkmaar (NL) LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/afilambert

Nationality Dutch

Birth date May 19, 1983

Place of birth Alkmaar, Netherlands

Proficient in dutch and english Language



Profile

Full stack web developer and solution architect with 15 years of experience in the Amsterdam metropolitan area. My focus is on creating elegant, open source and high performance solutions for enterprises and startups. I have a wide interest in technology and people tell me I have good communication skills. My technical experience include:

★ Front-end development

React, Next.js, Apollo Client, Relay.js, CSS-in-JS, Jest, Webpack, Svelte, JWT, A/B testing, tag-management, GDPR, WebDriver, Puppeteer

★ Backend development

GraphQL, Node.js, Express, Apollo Server, Server Side Rendering, OAuth, SEO, Python, Flask, Django Rest Framework, Siege, Loader.io

★ Data processing

Machine learning, Apache Kafka, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, image processing, Redis, Google Analytics, bcrypt

★ Hosting and devops

Google Cloud, CI/CD, Varnish, Nginx, HAProxy, uWSGI, git, Linux, MacOS

Experience

Tellow - Solution architect (freelance)

Nov. 2018 - Oct. 2019 in Utrecht

Tellow is a **fintech startup** backed by Rabobank. The company provides an efficient and affordable bookkeeping-tool for freelancers.

The marketing website (<u>tellow.nl</u>) was very slow and in need of a redesign. The new, static SPA website was generated with the **Gatsby** framework using a headless CMS and provides a super fast experience. With a serverless Google **Cloud Function** running an Apollo **GraphQL-service**, the website is able to accept user input.

To provide a better user experience for customers and reduce costs I implemented a **machine learning** algorithm using Tensorflow. The neural network used classification on invoice scans to create bookings without the need for humans. The solution used several microservices communicating via binary **event streams** using the CQRS and event-sourcing patterns. Technologies used included Apache Kafka, Node.js, protocol buffers and GraphQL-subscriptions.

Takeaway - Solution engineer (freelance)

Feb. 2019 - Sept. 2019 in Alkmaar

Takeaway is known as thuisbezorgt.nl in the Netherlands, the service makes it easy to order meals from local restaurants. I build a **secure and high-performant GraphQL** service that securely stores your favorite restaurants. The focus for this project was to lay a solid foundation which the team used to connect more internal REST-services.

Telegraaf.nl - Technical lead and platform architect

2014 - Jan. 2019 in Amsterdam

Telegraaf is one of the most read online news resources in the Netherlands. With over 1 billion pageviews per month it is truly a **high traffic** service.

During my time at Telegraaf.nl my team (13 developers in 2 agile subteams) and I took a greenfield approach and **transformed the complete stack**. We moved from a monolithic application build on top a proprietary CMS, to an API first **service oriented architecture**. A loosely coupled content repository, an editorial frontend (React) and backend (Drupal **headless API**) a new Progressive web app (PWA) frontend (Relay.js), Backend as a Service (GraphQL) and image-scaling service (Thumbor) were build. The new stack was **horizontally scalable**, **high available**, properly **performance tested** and was put into production without major issues. Telegraaf was acquired by Mediahuis after which I oversaw the **complete platform** and

integration of services. Technical leads from all teams collaborated via our **Architecture Guild**, which I supervised.

TuinTuin - Co-founder and CTO

2011 – present in Alkmaar

TuinTuin.nl is a community where garden professionals and garden owners meet each other and share their best photos, ideas and projects. I've build the complete solution and I try to keep it up to date with the latest technologies. The website uses Responsive web design (RWD), **monorepo**, **internationalization** (i18n), **NoSQL** (Firestore) and is build using Node.js and Flask. We host our services on **Google Cloud** and use Jest for testing.

TMG - Sr. Web Developer

2007 – 2014 in Amsterdam

I advised the business and my colleagues on technical solutions for various projects. Some brands I have worked on include hyses.nl (high volume, Hadoop, MapReduce, HipHop for PHP), speurders.nl (high available, php-fpm, Symfony, MariaDB), metronieuws.nl (Drupal), Speurdersindekrant.nl (WYSIWYG, js calendar, J2EE) and relatioplanet.nl (.NET, Microsoft SQL Server). I worked on the full stacks including devops work in our private cloud (Varnish, Nginx, HAProxy, uWSGI, setting up CI/CD).

Other work

- ★ Instant Magazine freelance frontend developer. Hubspot CMS, SEO
- ★ Lila Concepts co-founder. Websites using Wordpress in finance and health-sectors
- ★ BinckBank freelance full stack developer. Hosting with AWS, gulp, nunjucks
- ★ Site Promotor co-founder. Improved SEO/SERP for hundreds of clients
- ★ Genster Groep freelance web developer. Flash, ActionScript
- ★ Lambert Consultancy self employed. Several projects

Education and courses

2017	Certified Scrum Product Owner	Amsterdam	Xebia Academy
2016	Certified Scrum Master	Amsterdam	Gladwell, scrum.org
2010	Hackers Mindset	Amsterdam	Certified Secure
2009	Basis Management Opleiding	Amsterdam	Schouten en Nelissen
2008	Advanced HTML	Amsterdam	Twice IT Training
2008	Java Programming 1 + 2	Nieuwegein	5hart IT Opleidingen
2001 – 2007	Computer Science BSc	Haarlem	InHolland University
2006	Drivers license B	Heiloo	Rijschool M&L

Interests and hobbies

I like having quality time with my girlfriend Jantina and our daughter Jet. We often sail our sloop over the beautiful canals of Alkmaar. We have a beautiful home in the city center where we often go out. Occasionally I need to get my hands dirty while gardening, but I like to work on our online garden community <u>TuinTuin.nl</u> even more.